Welcome to Market Leader. Today we are going to
talk about ICICI Lombard General
Insurance. Friends, this company
is a joint venture between ICICI Bank Limited and
Fairfax Finance Shareholding Limited. You
can see that Chandan Kochhar is the Chairman
and Director of ICICI
General Insurance. This company has expanded its products in general insurance.
Friends, motor insurance, health insurance,
travel insurance, medical insurance, home
insurance, and other products. Claims and
wellness are customer support products.
Friends, the company and ICICI Lombard
also presented their net profit results for Q1.
Friends, their results and their
net worth have jumped by 80%. Friends,
they have made a net profit of Rs 349 crore.
But even after making such a profit, they could
not beat the estimates.
Friends, you can see that they could
not beat the market estimates. They missed it. You
can see that there has been a good crash.
Friends, it
closed at 1216 yesterday. Friends, there may be a
slight decline today as well.
Friends, we are giving it a target of Rs 15. But
this stock can make a good profit going forward.
Friends, because all these insurance companies  The
face has also just been listed friends, two-
four years ago, now we come to the company and the
market capitalization of the company is friends
59750 crores, its face value is 10, it can
give split bonus in the feature and this company is
sitting on dividend to its shareholders,
friends and you can see that Sher Khan is
giving a target of 1500 for ICICI Lombard General Insurance
and Motilal Oswal is also giving
1500, but this share can make
you tremendous wealth in the long term above 2000,
friends, you must keep an eye on this share
and this is an
ICICI group company of ICICI Bank Group,
friends, so this share can make you a good belt in the long term,
now as soon as we come to the
share holding pattern of the company,
48% or 526% 13% and see the public, 11.35
%, so friends, the company has a strong share holding pattern
and now we come to the
company, you can see that the company is
continuously increasing its revenue
and in 2022 the company has made tremendous jam  It has generated
revenue of 14000 to 66 crores and
last year it was 13700 crores, so there
is a jump of almost 4000 crores, friends. And look at the net profit, it is
so good, even after generating revenue, there
is a decline in net profit, friends. You
can see that the network
made a net profit of 1271 crores last year. You can see that
this company is a debt-free
company, friends. The company works on zero interest.
And now we come to the company, you can see that the company is
continuously growing, my friend. The
company currently has an
available capital of 89708 crores, friends. And you can see that the
company pays dividend to its regular or shareholder holders
twice a year. Friends, this company
gives final dividend and interim dividend twice to
its shareholders. You
can see that its peer companies are LIC,
India, SBI Life, HDFC Life,
ICICI Prudential, but the
business of all these companies is a little different and
their business model is a little different, friends. It works
in general insurance,
friends. And ICICI Prudential does
less in health claims etc.  It does,
friends,
you can see,
and now we are coming to the share price, it has
closed at 1222, friends, sorry, sorry, it is the
right of van month in van month,
friends, this stock has fallen by seven percent in van month,
friends, and it
closed yesterday at 1220 rupees, friends,
its 52 also closes, ₹100, and 52 also
ate 1675 and its target is giving,
friends, it can cross the 52 mark and
move ahead, friends, and see, in one year,
this stock is going down by 21%, friends,
and see, in 5 years, it has not given any such returns yet, it is
giving returns of 79.67%, 80%, friends,
and see the maximum, the stock was listed in the market in 2017 at
₹80 and from there it crossed 1500,
and from there it has had a good crash,
friends, it started recovering after the crash,
but this is because of the result,
friends, share it, and if you like this video, then
definitely like and share the video, do
not forget to subscribe to the channel.